The issue is that with generative AI,
the world is way more open. You can
create anything. But because you can
create anything, you also need to be
like super precise in your instruction.
Garbage in, garbage out. What do you put
into your prompt? What is the level of
details that you give or context? It's
all about context. And so, you're
opening yourself to way more mistake or
actually not just the right guidelines.
You're listening to the AI Native Dev,
brought to you by Tessian.
Hello and welcome to another episode of
the AI Native Dev. On today's show, we
have Roxanne Fischer, who's going to
talk to us a little bit about how AI can
assist us in our DevOps infrastructure
as code flows. Roxanne, welcome. How are
you?
Hi, nice to meet you. Good and you?
Yeah, doing well, thank you. You're the
co-founder and CEO of Anyshift. And in
fact, prior to that, you've done a huge
amount of research. And I think we
partly crossed paths a little bit before
as well with an acquisition from Sneak.
Tell us a little bit about your past.
I'm one of the co-founder of Anyshift.
We are a source graph connected to your
cloud. How to enhance visibility for
DevOps team
in the day-to-day workflow.
And so, personally, I'm an former AI
researcher. I was doing research in
fintech companies and also at Samsung in
vision and financial data. And when I
started actually the entrepreneurial
journey, I met my co-founder, Stefan,
whose previous company, Cloud Shift, who
created Drift CTL, was acquired by
Sneak. So, how was the road crossed?
Yeah.
And here we are. Started Anyshift a
couple months ago trying to bridge
actually this gap between DevOps and AI.
Yeah, amazing. And it's interesting when
when we think about AI and and how AI
dev tools can help our workflows and
help our our development, we
automatically think very quickly about
how we can write code faster, how we can
review code, and all those kind of
things. But there's a ton more which is
perhaps in the DevOps space and others
that are going to be very helpful to us
over time. First of all, how well
adopted do you think or or rather not
adopted necessarily, but how much do you
think people are are focusing on code
completion, almost too much, and coding
assistance, almost too much, where AI
can actually help us in various other
places of the CI/CD pipeline of DevOps
and things like that. Are we
over-rotating on coding assistance and
and under-utilizing AI in various other
places in the pipeline?
It's a good question. I think first of
all, like GenAI is great and enhances
all of our life, like the next one
another X faster.
And we should use it because I can doing
a new generation of code generation and
what capabilities we can create. But
there's still some issues about that. As
you said, you have so many more like
line of codes which are created now like
in an exponential way, which create like
issues about legacy. You can create
legacy code way faster and with like a
limited number of reviewers,
it's actually reviews the code which was
generated, which is actually even more
crucial and difficult with
infrastructure as code, where like it's
complicated to test your infra. Like the
layers of tests for your infra like that
doesn't mature, like it's more
complicated to do it than for
application.
And the other point is that with so many
lines of code which are now created,
like you also have a sense of ownership,
which is less important for different
developer teams. You don't even remember
sometimes the code that you have
created. So, those are new challenges.
And also if I complete to your question,
add something about that, it's
particular also like for infrastructure
as code, so we like it can help SREs,
DevOps team, engineering design for
because compared to like other
frameworks such as Python, Java,
infrastructure as code such as Terraform
is relatively new. Like Terraform is 10
years old.
Like when you go on GitHub, like you
only have 1,000 like couple of thousand
public models of Terraform.
Mhm.
Um the amount of code that was used to
actually train LLMs, those large
language models that do these sort of
completion, those generative models,
those asset are quite small compared to
other framework. One of the issue is
that nobody really wants to put their
infra on clear on GitHub. It's too
sensitive. And so,
the generation of infrastructure as code
framework won't be as good as for other
one.
So, is is generative AI, the way LLMs
are trained needing huge amounts of
data, for example, is that the right way
we should be thinking about AI in in the
infrastructure as code and the DevOps
space?
Yeah. The way your models are trained is
that actually they're going to train on
a large amount of data to understand
patterns. And they will understand like
large amount of patterns. The more data
you have, the better you are actually to
understand like similarities,
correlation between different framework.
One example and I like to take is that
you can create like some code, but
potentially because your amount of data
won't be big enough, you won't get like
the best type of generation of code as
that you could expect. So, one of the
few sandbox environments that we did at
Anyscale would be, okay, let's generate
a VPC peering between two different
VPCs.
And we're going actually to ask GPT to
create it. And it's going to do it. It's
going to work because it's still really
good and it still helps a lot in your
day-to-day. But when you do that, if you
don't give enough context, so you will
have the are hardcoded values of the
VPCs.
And also, you will miss some additional
information. Metadata, the auto accept
value is missing, and the tags also,
which don't help to create actually
these quality contents to be part of the
policies of your company. How you should
actually ensure an info which is
consistent, tags that are consistent, to
actually avoid future mistake in the
future. Like for instance, with those
hard-coded data, you're opening yourself
to future outages, with hard-coded value
dependencies. And so, some context is
still missing in terms of the quality of
the content that you're generating.
And I guess that's where you as a user
will want to use AI to as as a you need
to to provide the right levels of
information to the LLM, not just to make
sure it provides something accurate, but
actually
relevant to what you're trying to build.
And I think that's probably where I
would guess that interaction between the
LLM as a chat would likely work as well.
Tell us a little bit about something
called synthesis AI. That's something
that I know that you're very interested
in using that alongside generative AI.
Yes, so super interesting. And so, just
to make the difference on the speed
between the two, pretty much just like
the same technology is used behind it.
Um but, two words to actually point out
two ways of using those LLMs. You can
describe like synthesis AI about how you
actually synthesize information. So, as
input to your LLM, you're going to take
logs and other like metadata to actually
understand something and give some
insights. I want to do like a faster
like root cause analysis, like automatic
root cause analysis. I have an issue,
and so, this synthesis will actually
help me to go through like thousands and
hundreds of logs.
Whereas like for generative AI, you also
have an input, but rather than actually
like finding some insight, you want to
create something. You want to create
some code.
You're are going to ask in your prompt
to create a special configuration for
me. The issue is that with generative
AI, the world is way more open. You can
create anything. But because you can
create anything, you also need to be
like super precise in your instruction.
Garbage in, garbage out. What do you put
into your prompt?
What is the the level of details that
you give our context? It's all about
context. And so, you're opening yourself
to way more mistake or actually not just
the right guidelines. Synthesis AI, on
the contrary, is something that
we believe is more mature in the way of
you're taking a lot of information in,
huge amount of data,
and you want to find the patterns. Where
can I find this needle in the haystack?
And this is mature because at the end
like same technology LLMs that are going
to actually find or create some
insights, those patterns, but synthesis
is way more framed. So, you are going to
find information which is already
somewhere. Whereas like generative still
lacks some context, the context we've
been talking about.
Yeah, just to reflect that back. You use
the synthesis AI to effectively take in
huge amounts of data
and boil that down almost to insights.
And then pass those insights over to the
generative AI to effectively create
something based on those insights. And
that presumably avoids the problem of
then passing huge amounts of context to
the LLM where it may or may not use that
context wisely given we know LLMs aren't
great with large amounts of context. How
how does the synthesis AI how does that
deal with large amounts of context?
The way you're going to do it is that as
you said, you have different flows. You
can use synthesis AI, find insight, and
then take it as input to generate some
code. Or you can give other way other
windows of context. It can be like the
output of like synthesis AI or something
else.
The way it works, let's say synthesis is
just a word that I use to make the
distinction. That was actually like
referred to in different articles, but
to say that you can consider two
different pillars for using those LLMs.
Synthesis would be exactly used the same
way as generative, like using for
instance GPT to do but instead of using
a prompt with a guideline, create some
code. Your prompt would be to say, "I'm
going to take into input all my logs and
now search inside it, find me as a
different correlation connection
potential issue about one specific
configuration among all of them." One
actually other thing which is
interesting about that is how you can
link it and actually it's the same
principle as RAG with Retrieval
Augmented Generation principle which are
used in AI to actually elaborate
contents information and then find in
this content information.
Mhm.
So, the same way like you I'm speaking
about synthesis AI integrating some logs
and finding some patterns. One of the
technology that a lot of people use
nowadays to actually answer to complex
question with a lot of input data is to
before like actually asking this
question, do an entire processing of
this amount of data. So, it can be logs,
it can be something else, can be
document,
anything that you are going to actually
encode. You are going to actually like
encompass information into latent spaces
which are used in AI to encode
information and then query it. And so,
this entire process of RAG is going to
be done after doing this processing,
query faster a huge amount of
information.
And with that large amount of
information, we've talked a few times in
the past about determinism and the
determinism and non-deterministic output
from the LLMs. In terms of being able to
have that deterministic mapping, I
guess, to the rag. Talk us through you
know, what's available there for us.
Yeah, deterministic is an interesting
topic because GenAI is probabilistic.
When you call an LLM,
it's going to give you an answer, but
with a probability of the answer. So,
you're never 100% sure that it's going
to be the same answer answer
by nature of those models. Deterministic
algorithm, on the contrary, will always
give you the same answer if you give the
same input. You need both to actually
generate quality content. Depending on
your use case, of course, but so when
you imagine that you have like
infrastructure with thousands of cloud
resources, so many configuration, having
a deterministic context that you
actually know about is as important as
also having this LLM, large language
model, which will give you some insight
about it or generate some code about it.
What's interesting about your
infrastructure, so depending on what you
do, is that your cloud resources,
Kubernetes oneness, etc., again it's
going to be a graph. It's a way that
those resources are connected. You have
a VPC and within a subnet and you have
IAMs and everything all those resources
are like interconnected and you can
actually represent them as a graph of
interconnected nodes. If I take back the
example about this VPC peering, the way
you understand that everything is
related, you need to represent it as a
graph. And if you want to generate some
content or get insight about it, so
imagine I want to generate best
practiced code for this VPC peering with
no hardcoded value, I need to have the
context of where actually the other
resources that I'm going to refer to, so
dependencies, reside in this graph.
Right.
And so, I need to have these contexts,
deterministic context, about my own
infra on my own content, my own
documents, anything to
then generate quality content or get the
right information inside about it.
Yeah. Yeah, uh very interesting. Okay,
so that's so it's almost like the
determinism is built in there, I guess.
You're adding the the outcomes you would
expect almost and then having AI to pick
a path effectively to provide that
determinism. Is that Is that fair?
Yes, because otherwise it's all about
context. If you don't give this context,
your LM can do anything. It's so
powerful that it can generate anything.
It can
create like some pattern code,
infrastructure as code, documents, all
within the same model. You can have like
more specialized smaller models, but
still super powerful. If you want to
have a precise answer uh to complex
queries, you need to give like precise
context. And so, this context is all
like you put it in your prompts, I want
this and that, but so you need to
actually rephrase everything, so it
would be the equivalent of coding
yourself something. Or you need to plug
in as inputs these deterministic
contents, your own knowledge, like your
enterprise knowledge, to actually be
able to create these very precise
quality contents.
Yeah, really interesting. And I think
we're like flowing from the today of how
people can use AI to like almost looking
forward as to how we expect people in
the DevOps space to use it. Let's go
through a couple of examples where we
kind of talk about a couple of flows
that we would expect folks to who are
listening to very much resonate with.
Why don't we start with the idea that
perhaps there's an issue or something
like that in our deployment or our
infrastructure somewhere. We would have
a ton of data through our logs. We'll be
doing a lot of our root cause analysis
trying to identify where the main issue
came from. And what tools would you say
developers and ops folks should be
looking at or considering to be able to
analyze or rather even use the AI to
analyze that kind of level of data that
we know we can get from production
systems.
It depends of which time of teams you're
speaking of
Mhm.
because I think like the world is open
and so it depends of what do you
integrate as inputs. The more info you
have as a better. You have like many
startups and we're also building it that
are working on that and I guess you are
too. In term of actually how do you take
so many input data to actually analyze
it and the more the better. Logs,
metadata, clouds, APIs, communities.
Everything you have even like customer
supports. I have an application which is
laggy in my front end. How do I
correlate this signal? So it's like a
text, a complaint with some logs about
latency. And how I take all these
heterogeneous data, use it as inputs to
my models and being able to find back
these insights, these correlation. And I
guess for me it's one of the biggest
strength of these models. It's amazing
at actually integrating heterogeneous
data and this is why like this synthesis
AI principle for me is like ready. And
we have like different tools which are
really good at doing this root cause
analysis, especially good at actually
analyzing logs.
Mhm.
And so
depending of once you will get all the
different information you can have but
it's at the end a lot of work in term of
infrastructure, what do you integrate in
your pipeline? So integration but once
you have integrated everything, how
you're able to dump everything, encode
it and actually being able to query it.
Any tools you'd call out there in terms
of the root cause analysis or the triage
space looking through log lines?
I've heard recently about Cluvio. That's
IO. Never used it but I think it's good.
And you have also all the big players
such as DataDog that are like you know
leveraging AI to read logs.
Yeah.
And you have also like many startups
like doing that on Kubernetes, also.
Yeah, yeah, cool. If we take a question
about almost a an organizational
question. When we think about how over
the years with DevOps, we're trying to
get developers closer to their
production environments and trying to
get them more involved in that overall
deployment, understanding the
infrastructure, and so forth.
Do do you feel like there's an issue in
and around ownership? Uh where the more
we expect developers to use AI in
creating their infrastructure and and
creating their deployment artifacts,
that they actually lose that ownership
or lose that connection more with the
final production because in some sense,
they're using effectively AI to push
production away or push the ops leave
the ops to the AI. Is that a problem or
is that not not necessarily one?
Yeah, I find it interesting because I
think it's a problem, but also like it
comes with a lot of benefits of AI. I
think like at an issue we like more than
50% of our code is generated by cloud.
And it's about what you make out of out
of it, what do you use like as a prompt,
and you're able to actually code faster.
But the thing is because of that,
because you're so much more efficient,
how can you remember everything you have
done? I don't have a clear answer to
that. I'm myself trying to figure out. I
think we need like more safety nets. We
have for instance, so other example
about generating infrastructure as code
content. Imagine like your prompt is
really bad or like your model is not
super good, and you are going to create
like some open bots to everything. And
so, super bad practice.
Because it's probabilistic and you're
not 100% sure about the code you're
going to create, you still need those
safety nets, check out sneak uh to
actually be sure that you don't rely
100% on something which is still
non-deterministic. And we can speak
about potential security flaws that it
can also create. So, how to always have
like different
ways of actually safeguarding yourself
from attacks from bad configuration. And
in terms of ownership, how to actually
enhance the ownership of different
people making some like generating
contents. It's not obvious because
you're getting more like efficient, you
still need to actually own your code
and you need to remember what you have
pushed and why you have done it. If you
don't even remember which line of code
you have generated, that's an issue.
Yeah, no absolutely. Let's now take a
little look going forward. We obviously
mentioned the kernel using rag a lot
more. I'm really interested there in
terms of that determinism that you can
pull out using that. What do you feel
like are some of the future trends in
this space particularly around your work
with with any shift?
We sincerely believe that the future of
AI/DevOps resides in two pillar.
AI but also the determinacy part. It's
the more like infrastructure part.
And you need both to have this context
plus also like the power of AI. And so,
because your infrastructure is a graph
is the type of it like
your cloud resources, everything that
are interconnected, the like definition
and different like providers, DNS etc.
that are linked to it. We believe that
to create the best of it, to generate
content for DevOps team
and also like to remediate to some
issues, we need to create and work on
those both pillars. In the determinacy
part
this graph and then the query and the
remediation with AI.
In term of the graph and also I believe
this is where it's important to have
like some knowledge about your space and
like how you're going to create it. The
schema of your graph is important.
The different dependencies between your
nodes and your edges to represent some
cloud resources
can be done in many ways. You can
connect a VPC with a subnet with an
edge,
but you can also connect them because
they have they have similar tags.
For instance, data team, I don't know.
So, the schema of this graph, how you
connect components and what you put in
inside it, is super important because
it's also how you're going to query it.
How you're going to retrieve
information. Because to actually do this
remediation and code generation for SRE
teams, you need to first create this
context, this graph, this schema. And
then do the queries. And how do you
query it? I want to get all the
information of all the dependencies of
this specific EC2 in the last 24 hours
and the team who owns it that has
created a change.
To be able to query and to have an
answer to those specific and global or
local queries,
you need to have a schema that is
actually adaptable to those queries. How
to have to actually go fetch information
in the
fastest and like more accurate way.
Mhm. And so, do you pair those two then?
Is that something you use as a schema to
almost validate or is that something
that you then pass directly into the LLM
to say, "Look, here's some information
about the data or about the
configurations. You use this to be able
to query. Use this to be able to
understand."
And
that's interesting because the schema we
define ourselves because this is where
we believe is the value of having some
knowledge about how your infrastructure
work is. So, how do you connect things
and how you're going to query them
afterward? One of the fun parts is that
to actually enhance development and make
it faster, we use AI also like
internally and to actually populate this
graph. When the schema is in place, how
do you actually like leverage AI to pass
some data and to actually populate your
graph?
Awesome. So, tell us a little bit about
AnyShift and and the area, the space
that your mission and the space that's
in.
So,
as you know, we still want to give back
some visibility to SRE teams, to answer
actually to key questions, simple
questions that are still hard to answer
nowadays, such as like, where is this
resource defined in my code base? Who
owns it? What are its dependencies?
But between like cloud resources,
Kubernetes one, DNS, data providers,
etc. And the way we do it is that we're
going to create this digital twin of
your infrastructure. And from that you
will be able something similar to a
resource catalog, be able to actually
like query your graph to answer to this
question. We begin with something which
is like a very shift-left approach,
something very similar also to sneak or
like other tools, how to actually like
prevent issue before it happen, or give
you like at least more information and
visibility at your change before you
deploy it. And so, we're going to
integrate within your pull request
to actually, once you make a change,
query this graph, query this map of
dependency, and give you more context
about actually what you have done. And
okay, you have changed like this stuff
on module,
it's going to affect like other
resources or repository, should you
really do it? And so, the AI part that
we're going to leverage is actually on
the educational content. So, something
similar to synthesis AI we were speaking
about. You have all this information.
You you graph, you have all these
dependencies, complex. And your teams
are
pretty less aware of the entire context
of your infrastructure. And so, how do
you use AI to actually explain what
happened?
And based on this context that we
provide, also to the explainability
based on that.
How can people have a play with Any
Shift? Is it available today? Can people
get involved?
So, the way we work is that now you can
actually already test Any Shift on our
platform if you are like going to
subscribe,
and actually what we're building first
would be like this deterministic part of
your graph. So, giving all of these the
dependencies of the impact zone of your
change.
I think you said 50% of the code in any
shift is written by Claude, is that
right?
Yeah, yeah.
Okay, tell us a little bit about that
then cuz you know, it's interesting
sometimes I think Google or or or
someone recently said 25% of the code
that they write is written by AI. I'd
love to hear a little bit more about the
the 50%
of code that's written by AI.
How how are you using AI internally at
Infracheck today? Is Is it mostly on the
code creation or a bit of everything
through the pipeline?
Actually both.
First of all, we are like in Go, and so
all of our developers don't necessarily
are expert in Go. And like an LLM is
that amazing translator in any kind of
language.
So, how do you like ask something? You
You need at the end to know exactly what
you want. And your LLM will create 80%
of what you need, and you will then need
to be able to do the review. Which
actually accelerate accelerate the
development a lot. But this is like all
the developers now do it nowadays. The
other part that we are doing in a more
conscious way is to actually
automatically use LLMs to pass some code
and some content to then actually
generate our graph.
Which is something which is a little bit
more specific.
Yeah, yeah. Interesting. How How How
have you found using Do you Do you have
best practices or what what what advice
would you give to people who are trying
to add AI capabilities into their
workflows today?
I think my conclusion would be that
people need to It's when you do a a
recurrence, you have test case number
one, test case number two, and then you
can do like the n plus one for loop. You
need to understand very precisely what
you want to do because
then you will understand the edge cases,
and then you will be able to actually
ask your model exactly what you need as
the best way, but it's easy to
go straight away to your model, ask
something, and think it's going to do
magic, and sometimes it does.
Yeah.
But if you want to do something at
scale, be super aware with like first
age cases, and number one, number two,
what you want, what's going to be the
output, and then you understand the
patterns, let's go.
Yeah, amazing. So, still brain of in a
very attended fashion.
Yes, but
everything is in coding, so
Yeah.
I guess like potentially these comments
will not be relevant
if
in two months, yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Amazing. Roxane, thank you very much for
the session, and I'm looking forward to
the demo actually of AnyShift. So, for
those who are interested in that, please
do check out the YouTube channel, and
you'll see the YouTube video. It's only
YouTube, but the YouTube video of of
AnyShift in action as well. So, thank
you very much, Roxane, and thanks
everyone for tuning in. And we'll see
you again next time.
Thank you.
Thanks for tuning in. Join us next time
on the AI Native Dev, brought to you by
Tessi.